Contact

Bengaluru, Karnataka roshan.halwai@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/roshanhalwai (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

С

C++

Data Structures

Languages

English

Tamil

Hindi

Certifications

Fundamentals of SQL and PLSQL JAVA SE6

Honors-Awards

Best Outgoing Student Best Team Member Applause Award

Roshan Halwai

Software Development Engineer 2 at Amazon Bengaluru

Summary

Roshan is a computer geek credited with strong ability to solve complex problems with optimal solutions. He believes in making this world a better place to live not only by extensive use of technology but also through act of kindness.

He considers himself as a working and proactive person with professional and humanistic potential for providing solutions and is very passionate about coding and problem solving.

His areas of Expertise are in the field of Data Structures, Algorithms, System Design, Compiler Design and Modernizing legacy applications.

His favorite programming languages are C, C++, Java and Android.

Experience

Amazon
Software Development Engineer 2
March 2020 - Present (6 months)
Andhra Pradesh, India

Deloitte Consulting

2 years 6 months

Senior Software Engineer June 2019 - February 2020 (9 months) Bangalore

- Assisted in the development of technology roadmaps to evolve the API estate in conjunction with internal and external solution providers.
- Worked as a technical expert with clients, analysts, programmers and other team members to develop technical solutions to complex business problems.
- Maintained corporate standards for deploying technology and worked with senior management in strategic planning.

Software Engineer

September 2017 - September 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Bengaluru Area, India

- Involved in development of a compiler that could convert one programming language to another.
- Developed software migration tools for legacy systems primarily in Java;
- Applied efficient data structure and algorithms to ensure the compiler is not compromised in terms of its performance.

Tata Consultancy Services

2 years 4 months

System Engineer

September 2016 - August 2017 (1 year)

Chennai Area, India

- Understood the requirements from the Client and Onshore lead
- Prepared the design for the Adapter which followed MT Connect Standards
- Analyzed which Programming Language (C++/C#) will be suitable for the development of this Service
- Developed the Window Service right from scratch and ensured the service ran 24/7 without any manual intervention
- Made sure the service generated logs so that in case of issues, tracking can be done easily.
- Prepared test data to execute test cases on the service.
- Tested the Service by fetching data from more than 5 CNC Machines.
- Involved in defect reporting and weekly status reporting.
- Conducted both Manual Testing and Automated Testing
- Involved in Functional and Regression Testing of the Application

Assistant System Engineer

May 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 5 months)

Chennai Area, India

- Followed Agile methodologies for migration of the Branch Applications
- Migrated around 30 Modules from 16-Bit to 32-Bit
- Ensured the User Interface and the functionality of modules were not compromised
- Debugged the code and found root cause of the severe issues
- Gained strong grip of Windows Applications, Multi-Threading and Servicing
- Involved in preparing bug report and interaction with testing team
- Participated in Bug Review Meetings

Education

M.Kumarasamy College of Engineering

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Information Technology · (2011 - 2015)